<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<posts>
  <row Id="1" PostTypeId="1" AcceptedAnswerId="3" CreationDate="2010-09-13T19:27:46.227" Score="14" ViewCount="235" Body="&lt;p&gt;Are questions that belong to the category &quot;What Apps Should I Get?&quot; appropriate Android Enthusiasts? How about if they're asking for specific apps, such as &quot;What are good RSS aggregator apps that integrate with Google Reader and allow offline reading?&quot;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;" OwnerUserId="36" LastEditorUserId="440" LastEditDate="2013-06-05T06:10:40.070" LastActivityDate="2013-06-05T06:10:40.070" Title="Are &quot;What Apps Should I Get?&quot; Questions Appropriate?" Tags="&lt;discussion&gt;&lt;faq&gt;&lt;scope&gt;&lt;questions&gt;" AnswerCount="10" CommentCount="2" FavoriteCount="2" />
  <row Id="2" PostTypeId="2" ParentId="1" CreationDate="2010-09-13T19:56:02.163" Score="2" Body="&lt;p&gt;Most I have seen are list of X questions, and likely should be closed. Many answers are non-authoriatative and subjective, including my own on a GPS/traffic question.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;It seems to be an abuse to simply make this a request board for app suggestions.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;" OwnerUserId="80" LastActivityDate="2010-09-13T19:56:02.163" CommentCount="2" />
  <row Id="3" PostTypeId="2" ParentId="1" CreationDate="2010-09-13T19:57:25.660" Score="7" Body="&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;No!&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Why?&lt;/strong&gt; Because there's no wrong answer, so anything would go.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Does this mean I just add a bunch of rules to narrow the scope and then it is allowed?&lt;/strong&gt; Well still no, because answers tend to be valued for how much people like the mentioned app, not the usefulness or quality of the answer.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Wouldn't making it community wiki solve the problem?&lt;/strong&gt; Again nope! Community Wiki is meant for questions that don't have a definitive answer and thus need some room for discussion or when the answers would benefit from collaboration of the community. The fact that there's no rep, doesn't change the fact that votes no longer equal quality, which is what our engine is designed for.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;So what to do?&lt;/strong&gt; Try asking a question that invites quality answers, that limits the amount of answers (it should be limited to one page of answers) and that explain how the app fits your specific needs.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;" OwnerUserId="20" LastActivityDate="2010-09-13T19:57:25.660" CommentCount="0" />
  <row Id="4" PostTypeId="2" ParentId="1" CreationDate="2010-09-13T20:14:46.383" Score="3" Body="&lt;p&gt;If they are subjective, then they should at the least be community wiki.  Or closed, depending on how &quot;generic&quot; or &quot;specific&quot; the question is.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;" OwnerUserId="10" LastActivityDate="2010-09-13T20:14:46.383" CommentCount="0" />
  <row Id="5" PostTypeId="1" CreationDate="2010-09-13T20:21:20.310" Score="8" ViewCount="395" Body="&lt;blockquote&gt;&#xA;  &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Possible Duplicate:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br&gt;&#xA;  &lt;a href=&quot;https://android.meta.stackexchange.com/questions/141/write-and-elevator-pitch-tagline&quot;&gt;Write and Elevator Pitch / Tagline&lt;/a&gt;  &lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;/blockquote&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;h2&gt;Note:&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;We are closing this domain naming thread. It is asking the &lt;em&gt;entirely&lt;/em&gt; wrong question. See this blog post for details: &lt;a href=&quot;http://blog.stackoverflow.com/2010/10/domain-names-the-wrong-question/&quot;&gt;Domain Names: Wrong Question&lt;/a&gt; &lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;We're going to keep the name android.stackexchange.com. But we WILL be setting up redirects from the more &quot;popular&quot; domains names. (e.g. seasonedadvice.com to cooking.stackexchange.com, basicallymoney.com to money.stackexchange.com, and others as we go through the list).&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;New question: &quot;&lt;strong&gt;Write and Elevator Pitch / Tagline!&lt;/strong&gt;&quot;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://android.meta.stackexchange.com/questions/141/write-and-elevator-pitch-tagline&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Click here to contribute ideas and vote.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;[original message text below]&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;hr&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Post your ideas for a dot-com domain name for this website, which captures the spirit and intent of the site, namely:&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;blockquote&gt;&#xA;  &lt;p&gt;{name} is intended for enthusiasts,&#xA;  power users, and regular people using&#xA;  the Android operating system.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;/blockquote&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Please follow these guidelines:&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Check to see if the domain is taken before making the name suggestion&lt;/strong&gt;. Taken names, however clever, are not helpful. You can use whois.net to check availability. (Read this &lt;a href=&quot;http://blog.stackoverflow.com/2010/07/domain-names/&quot;&gt;post&lt;/a&gt; regarding squatted names).&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Post one domain per answer&lt;/strong&gt;. This makes the voting process much easier. If domains are very similar (e.g. &quot;dev&quot; and &quot;devs&quot;), they can be in the same answer.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Make sure the domain wasn't already suggested&lt;/strong&gt;. To search within this question, use a search query such as: &lt;code&gt;inquestion:1 &quot;example.com&quot;&lt;/code&gt; replacing &lt;code&gt;example.com&lt;/code&gt; with the domain to search for.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;When coming back to this question, make sure to sort the answers &quot;newest first&quot;&lt;/strong&gt;, as to not miss new proposals.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;" OwnerUserId="10" LastEditorUserId="-1" LastEditDate="2017-03-16T15:45:42.413" LastActivityDate="2012-10-06T01:15:05.133" Title="What should our domain be?" Tags="&lt;discussion&gt;&lt;site-promotion&gt;" AnswerCount="18" CommentCount="9" FavoriteCount="1" ClosedDate="2010-10-08T20:59:41.350" />
  <row Id="6" PostTypeId="1" AcceptedAnswerId="7" CreationDate="2010-09-13T21:32:12.337" Score="31" ViewCount="484" Body="&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://stackoverflow.com&quot;&gt;Stack Overflow&lt;/a&gt; already has lots of questions regarding Android programming. Should this site try to stick to questions about using/owning an Android device, rather than developing for it? Or is the idea to include anything about Android devices?&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;" OwnerUserId="111" LastEditorUserId="267" LastEditDate="2012-10-05T20:17:54.420" LastActivityDate="2017-01-04T15:02:05.653" Title="Are Android programming questions for this site or Stack Overflow?" Tags="&lt;discussion&gt;&lt;faq&gt;&lt;scope&gt;" AnswerCount="4" CommentCount="0" FavoriteCount="1" />
  <row Id="7" PostTypeId="2" ParentId="6" CreationDate="2010-09-13T21:58:04.510" Score="31" Body="&lt;p&gt;My two cents:&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;If the question is programming related, SO makes the most sense to me.  This may be a fair place for input regarding user interface questions during app development, though, so long as you can keep the question from being overly subjective.  This is a site for Android users (and power users), not necessarily programmers.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;" OwnerUserId="116" LastActivityDate="2010-09-13T21:58:04.510" CommentCount="0" />
  <row Id="8" PostTypeId="2" ParentId="6" CreationDate="2010-09-13T22:26:35.200" Score="0" Body="&lt;p&gt;Unless/until &lt;a href=&quot;http://area51.stackexchange.com/proposals/7418/android-developers&quot;&gt;the Android Developers suggestion at Area 51&lt;/a&gt; takes off, I think SO should be used for development questions.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;" OwnerUserId="14" LastActivityDate="2010-09-13T22:26:35.200" CommentCount="1" />
  <row Id="9" PostTypeId="2" ParentId="1" CreationDate="2010-09-13T23:09:08.603" Score="0" Body="&lt;p&gt;If the question in subjective, I generally agree with Ivo Flipse's answer, though I think there are usually good ways to re-phrase the question that are not subjective:  Instead of &quot;Which dinosaur app...&quot;, you could ask &quot;What are the differences between these three dinosaur apps?&quot; or &quot;Are there any dinosaur apps?&quot;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;(Sorry, Dinosaurs were the first random topic that came to mind.  I must be a five year old.)&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;" OwnerUserId="116" LastActivityDate="2010-09-13T23:09:08.603" CommentCount="2" />
  <row Id="10" PostTypeId="2" ParentId="1" CreationDate="2010-09-13T23:17:19.577" Score="-3" Body="&lt;p&gt;Generic or specific questions should be made community. Like &quot;What's the best traffic app?&quot;. Questions like &quot;What apps should I get?&quot; should be closed.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;" OwnerUserId="14" LastActivityDate="2010-09-13T23:17:19.577" CommentCount="3" />
</posts>