<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<posts>
  <row Id="1" PostTypeId="1" CreationDate="2013-12-17T21:07:26.187" Score="2" ViewCount="105" Body="&lt;p&gt;As the community forms, it is important to define a specific set of guidelines for what is in-scope and what is out-of-scope for questions.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;" OwnerUserId="26" LastEditorUserId="1467" LastEditDate="2015-04-15T13:47:17.130" LastActivityDate="2015-04-15T13:47:17.130" Title="What are the general in-scope and out-of-scope guidelines?" Tags="&lt;discussion&gt;" AnswerCount="1" CommentCount="0" ClosedDate="2015-04-18T22:34:31.883" />
  <row Id="2" PostTypeId="2" ParentId="1" CreationDate="2013-12-17T21:40:13.877" Score="11" Body="&lt;p&gt;Let's see what sorts of questions get asked and then - when there are concerns regarding a topic - start specific discussions regarding them.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Tag them &lt;a href=&quot;/questions/tagged/specific-question&quot; class=&quot;post-tag&quot; title=&quot;show questions tagged &amp;#39;specific-question&amp;#39;&quot; rel=&quot;tag&quot;&gt;specific-question&lt;/a&gt; and let folks present their arguments for and against including the question on the site. These can then serve as a guide for the folks answering, reviewing and closing questions, as well as the basis for future on/off-topic guidance in the help system.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;" OwnerUserId="8" LastActivityDate="2013-12-17T21:40:13.877" CommentCount="0" />
  <row Id="3" PostTypeId="1" AcceptedAnswerId="4" CreationDate="2013-12-17T22:36:01.823" Score="18" ViewCount="182" Body="&lt;p&gt;As an example, &lt;a href=&quot;https://aviation.stackexchange.com/questions/9/i-just-busted-class-bravo-airspace-now-what&quot;&gt;I just busted class Bravo airspace, now what?&lt;/a&gt;, the accepted answer includes several US specific details (FAA, AOPA, ASRS). However, the question was not US specific.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;I expect this will become a bigger issue as we get more questions dealing with regulatory issues. If we do not have some sort of mechanism to specify which set of regulations a question is referring to, we will end up with questions which have multiple &quot;correct&quot; answers.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Does anyone have thoughts about how we should be handling country specific details? or if any special action is even required?&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;edit: Another possible US specific answer in: &lt;a href=&quot;https://aviation.stackexchange.com/questions/10/should-i-log-flight-time-as-a-passenger&quot;&gt;Should I log flight time as a passenger?&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;" OwnerUserId="48" LastEditorUserId="-1" LastEditDate="2017-04-13T12:59:58.800" LastActivityDate="2013-12-25T18:15:13.380" Title="How should we handle country specific questions answers?" Tags="&lt;discussion&gt;" AnswerCount="3" CommentCount="2" />
  <row Id="4" PostTypeId="2" ParentId="3" CreationDate="2013-12-17T22:36:01.823" Score="11" Body="&lt;p&gt;We should create tags for major aviation regulatory bodies on an as-needed basis. If a user wishes to ask about an issue in regards to a specific country, they should mention it in their question and tag it as such.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;If a question is not tagged, doesn't have a specific country or governing body mentioned, and the answer clearly depends on the local operating rules, we should use comments to ask for clarification and/or do our best to keep their responses as country-neutral as possible.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;" OwnerUserId="48" LastEditorUserId="69" LastEditDate="2013-12-25T18:15:13.380" LastActivityDate="2013-12-25T18:15:13.380" CommentCount="1" CommunityOwnedDate="2013-12-17T22:36:01.823" />
  <row Id="5" PostTypeId="2" ParentId="3" CreationDate="2013-12-17T22:48:20.157" Score="6" Body="&lt;p&gt;In many questions the applicable legislation will play a mayor role. I suggest to create tags representing the appropriate authorities. In the USA, that will be mostly the FAA, for Europe it will be mostly EASA. &lt;/p&gt;&#xA;" OwnerUserId="19" LastActivityDate="2013-12-17T22:48:20.157" CommentCount="0" />
  <row Id="6" PostTypeId="2" ParentId="3" CreationDate="2013-12-17T23:01:06.947" Score="4" Body="&lt;p&gt;I think that a lot of questions will not have very region-neutral answers, especially those that relate to regulations. As long as the answer calls out the regulatory body that it's using, or cites that country's regs, it seems like that &lt;em&gt;could&lt;/em&gt; be sufficient.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;" OwnerUserId="39" LastActivityDate="2013-12-17T23:01:06.947" CommentCount="7" />
  <row Id="7" PostTypeId="1" CreationDate="2013-12-17T23:03:14.207" Score="7" ViewCount="133" Body="&lt;p&gt;There is already one related question regarding military use of aircraft, flight systems, avionics, etc. on &lt;a href=&quot;http://area51.stackexchange.com/proposals/42572/aviation&quot;&gt;Area 51&lt;/a&gt; since this site's definition and commitment phase: &lt;a href=&quot;https://area51.meta.stackexchange.com/questions/11315/will-missiles-and-missiles-technology-be-a-part-of-this-aviation-and-aerospace&quot;&gt;Will missiles and missiles technology be a part of this Aviation and aerospace?&lt;/a&gt; Problem is, that the top rated answers there discuss that question from the perspective of the proposal's initial title: &lt;em&gt;&quot;Aviation and Aerospace&quot;&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;I agree with later &lt;a href=&quot;https://area51.meta.stackexchange.com/questions/11542/a-name-change-needed-but-to-what&quot;&gt;renaming of the proposal to Aviation alone&lt;/a&gt;, but that does leave us a bit in the dark with questions regarding scope that were discussed before that happened. Striking off &lt;em&gt;&quot;Aerospace&quot;&lt;/em&gt; from the title of our new site does change basic idea of the site quite a bit, so I'd like to know what the community here thinks of combat flight, military aircraft and military flight technology? Should they be within the scope of our website, or not? Can we provide satisfactory answers for such questions, or do we cater mostly to civil aviators, flight engineers, and alike?&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;" OwnerUserId="41" LastEditorUserId="-1" LastEditDate="2017-05-03T08:41:04.120" LastActivityDate="2014-11-24T11:53:02.247" Title="Are combat flight and military aircraft on scope?" Tags="&lt;discussion&gt;&lt;scope&gt;" AnswerCount="3" CommentCount="6" FavoriteCount="1" />
  <row Id="8" PostTypeId="1" CreationDate="2013-12-17T23:52:15.700" Score="13" ViewCount="117" Body="&lt;p&gt;I'm envisioning that we get quite a few questions regarding remote controlled aircraft - how should we respond to these questions? Are the on topic? Or do we want to keep the site to only life-sized aircraft?&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;" OwnerUserId="14" LastEditorUserId="3504" LastEditDate="2014-12-25T18:33:22.400" LastActivityDate="2014-12-25T18:33:22.400" Title="Are remote controlled aircraft on-topic?" Tags="&lt;discussion&gt;&lt;scope&gt;" AnswerCount="1" CommentCount="3" />
  <row Id="9" PostTypeId="1" CreationDate="2013-12-17T23:58:21.967" Score="3" ViewCount="63" Body="&lt;p&gt;Our &lt;a href=&quot;http://chat.stackexchange.com/rooms/12036/aviation&quot;&gt;main chat room&lt;/a&gt; has an option to include RSS / Atom feeds and display them as either:&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Message feeds&lt;/strong&gt;: New items from these feeds will be posted into the room like regular chat messages.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Ticker feeds&lt;/strong&gt;: New items from these feeds will be shown via a slide-down ticker overlay that periodically appears at the top of the room, and will not be persisted.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;These feeds can be managed by any of the Stack Exchange moderators or individual room owners and they can provide useful information to most of its members and keep conversations alive (or provide for new topics to chat about). So they are sort of important, but too many can also clutter the chat room or be even seen as spammy or otherwise unwanted. So I'm posting this question here for all of you to provide suggestions that we can vote on.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Please add new suggestions in the following format:&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;##Title&#xA;&#xA;URL to the RSS / Atom feed&#xA;&#xA;Short description&#xA;&#xA;---&#xA;&#xA;[Optional] Example feed item, either as formatted text or an image &#xA;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;With one suggestion per answer, and you can of course add multiple answers. Please don't duplicate suggestions! Sufficiently upvoted* suggestions will be added to our chat room and indicated as such by editing their title, attaching &quot;Added&quot; to it. If you would like to suggest what kind of feeds they should be added to (ticker or message feeds), please do so in their &lt;em&gt;Short description&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;*Suggestions posted below with a minimum of three votes that reach an equal or greater than &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Median&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow noreferrer&quot;&gt;median&lt;/a&gt; vote score out of all suggested feeds  will be included in our chatrooms's list of feeds.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;hr&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;I have already added two most common feeds to our &lt;a href=&quot;http://chat.stackexchange.com/rooms/12036/aviation&quot;&gt;main chat room&lt;/a&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://aviation.meta.stackexchange.com/feeds&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Recent Questions - Aviation Meta Stack Exchange&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; as a Message Feed and&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://aviation.stackexchange.com/feeds&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Recent Questions - Aviation Stack Exchange&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; as a Ticker Feed&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Meta questions are less frequent and should concern anyone in the Aviation main chat room, so I've added them to be included as normal chat messages, while the new questions of the Aviation main site could be too frequent and might not be interesting to all in the room, so I've added them as a &lt;em&gt;ticker feed&lt;/em&gt; that doesn't clutter the chat room's conversation space. This can of course be later changed, or removed altogether.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;" OwnerUserId="41" LastEditorUserId="-1" LastEditDate="2017-04-13T12:59:58.800" LastActivityDate="2013-12-22T19:34:26.853" Title="What feeds should our main chat include?" Tags="&lt;discussion&gt;&lt;chat&gt;" AnswerCount="8" CommentCount="1" FavoriteCount="1" />
  <row Id="10" PostTypeId="2" ParentId="9" CreationDate="2013-12-18T00:01:46.567" Score="0" Body="&lt;h2&gt;XKCD&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://xkcd.com/rss.xml&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow noreferrer&quot;&gt;http://xkcd.com/rss.xml&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://xkcd.com/&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow noreferrer&quot;&gt;XKCD&lt;/a&gt; comics display as &lt;em&gt;oneboxed&lt;/em&gt; images in Stack Exchange chats, meaning they have been thought of in advance and Stack Exchange chat software custom parses them for display purposes. In this case, they are displayed at their full width, or as much as it would fit in the chat window, instead of resized to maximum width for user added images that are much narrower. New XKCD images are usually posted daily, sometimes less frequently, but they certainly won't cutter the chat space.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Example feed&lt;/strong&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&lt;img src=&quot;https://i.stack.imgur.com/C3uTb.png&quot; alt=&quot;enter image description here&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;" OwnerUserId="41" LastEditorUserId="41" LastEditDate="2013-12-18T00:29:36.207" LastActivityDate="2013-12-18T00:29:36.207" CommentCount="0" />
</posts>