<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<posts>
  <row Id="1" PostTypeId="1" CreationDate="2012-04-25T18:22:40.743" Score="20" ViewCount="437" Body="&lt;p&gt;Some Stack Exchange sites have site-specific extensions that allow them e.g. to typeset mathematical equations, create UI mockups or display Go board positions. Some support for creating and displaying chemical formulas would be very useful here in my opinion.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;To convince SE to add support for that we should collect information about existing software that could be used for that. The requirements are, as far as I know:&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;It should be completely implemented in Javascript&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;It needs to be released under a compatible licence&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Which existing software could we use to make drawing and typing chemical formulas easier here?&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;" OwnerUserId="7" LastActivityDate="2013-10-04T14:38:08.060" Title="Which plugins for chemical formulas do we need?" Tags="&lt;feature-request&gt;&lt;discussion&gt;" AnswerCount="4" CommentCount="1" FavoriteCount="2" />
  <row Id="2" PostTypeId="2" ParentId="1" CreationDate="2012-04-25T18:23:02.693" Score="10" Body="&lt;p&gt;MathJax, which is already used by many SE sites supports the &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.ctan.org/pkg/mhchem&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;mhchem extension&lt;/a&gt; meant for typesetting chemical formulas like H&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt;O or [AgCl&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt;]&lt;sup&gt;-&lt;/sup&gt; using simple syntax like &lt;code&gt;\ce{H2O}&lt;/code&gt; or &lt;code&gt;\ce{[AgCl2]-}&lt;/code&gt;. We'll likely be using chemical formulas very often, so a simple way to enter them would be very useful.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Alternatively, an easier way of writing super- and subscripts could also work, and it would avoid relying on javascript postprocessing of the posts.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;" OwnerUserId="7" LastActivityDate="2012-04-25T18:23:02.693" CommentCount="8" />
  <row Id="3" PostTypeId="2" ParentId="1" CreationDate="2012-04-25T18:27:47.210" Score="13" Body="&lt;p&gt;The &lt;a href=&quot;http://web.chemdoodle.com/&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;ChemDoodle Web Components&lt;/a&gt; allow embedding an HTML5-based editor for structural formulas. It's released under the GPL, which should be suitable for SE as they don't distribute their software.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Having such an editor would be very valuable in my opinion, it would greatly simplify the workflow if one want's to include structural formulas. &lt;/p&gt;&#xA;" OwnerUserId="7" LastActivityDate="2012-04-25T18:27:47.210" CommentCount="0" />
  <row Id="5" PostTypeId="1" CreationDate="2012-04-25T19:04:21.857" Score="2" ViewCount="58" Body="&lt;p&gt;This is a bug, because an &quot;edit&quot; (at least to the extent that the user can make it) has already been made.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://i.stack.imgur.com/k00pm.png&quot; alt=&quot;enter image description here&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Is there anything that can be done to change this, perhaps for the first few days of the private beta reducing the rep that is required to review tag wiki edits?&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;" OwnerUserId="10" LastEditorUserId="22" LastEditDate="2012-06-23T13:20:32.757" LastActivityDate="2014-04-23T08:53:02.483" Title="Submitting a suggested edit for a tag, still results in a &quot;Tag has no wiki summary, can you help us create it?&quot;" Tags="&lt;bug&gt;&lt;feature-request&gt;&lt;status-bydesign&gt;" AnswerCount="2" CommentCount="1" ClosedDate="2012-05-30T00:58:12.803" />
  <row Id="6" PostTypeId="1" CreationDate="2012-04-25T19:12:39.290" Score="7" ViewCount="74" Body="&lt;p&gt;Many questions on Chemistry.SE will have to do with certain elements or molecules. In these situations, should the question be tagged with those names?&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;" OwnerUserId="16" LastActivityDate="2012-04-26T08:51:14.760" Title="Should we tag questions with elements they involve?" Tags="&lt;discussion&gt;&lt;tags&gt;" AnswerCount="3" CommentCount="0" FavoriteCount="1" />
  <row Id="8" PostTypeId="2" ParentId="6" CreationDate="2012-04-25T19:18:46.787" Score="14" Body="&lt;p&gt;My feeling is that in most cases, they will add little or nothing to the question, and should be avoided. I would be for tags like &lt;a href=&quot;https://chemistry.stackexchange.com/questions/tagged/halogens&quot; class=&quot;post-tag&quot; title=&quot;show questions tagged &amp;#39;halogens&amp;#39;&quot; rel=&quot;tag&quot;&gt;halogens&lt;/a&gt; that cover a number of elements, as those would much fewer in number, and would be used less often.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;As a rule, I would suggest that groups of things are OK (eg &lt;a href=&quot;https://chemistry.stackexchange.com/questions/tagged/aromatic-compounds&quot; class=&quot;post-tag&quot; title=&quot;show questions tagged &amp;#39;aromatic-compounds&amp;#39;&quot; rel=&quot;tag&quot;&gt;aromatic-compounds&lt;/a&gt;) but not single items.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;" OwnerUserId="10" LastActivityDate="2012-04-25T19:18:46.787" CommentCount="0" />
  <row Id="9" PostTypeId="1" CreationDate="2012-04-25T20:06:42.573" Score="7" ViewCount="434" Body="&lt;p&gt;I just asked a question regarding how protons remain together in a nucleus despite their electromagnetic repulsion, but &lt;a href=&quot;https://physics.stackexchange.com/questions/9661/protons-repulsion-within-a-nucleus&quot;&gt;I just found that exact question already asked and answered on Physics.SE&lt;/a&gt; Regrettably I deleted the question as it is an exact duplicate, but I thought I'd bring up the discussion here on meta.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;How do we decide where questions that straddle the physics/chemistry border belong? The field of particle physics seems like it could potentially belong on both sites, so how should we choose where specific questions should go? &lt;/p&gt;&#xA;" OwnerUserId="53" LastEditorUserId="-1" LastEditDate="2017-04-13T12:40:13.747" LastActivityDate="2012-04-28T22:35:51.870" Title="Where does Physics.SE end and Chemistry.SE begin?" Tags="&lt;discussion&gt;&lt;scope&gt;" AnswerCount="5" CommentCount="1" />
  <row Id="10" PostTypeId="2" ParentId="9" CreationDate="2012-04-25T20:24:29.557" Score="6" Body="&lt;p&gt;I believe the canonical criterion is that chemistry deals with chemical bonds. So, you need electrons, and you typically needs more than one atom. But there is some leeway, in that questions about the evolution of, say, ionization energy along the periodic table can be considered a chemistry or a physics question.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;My position would thus be: if it concerns molecules (more than one atom), chemical bonds, intermolecular or intramolecular interactions, we don't migrate it to Physics. If it concerns atomic properties, we migrate unless it's a question about the difference between various chemical elements (which is a fine chemistry question, somehow).&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;" OwnerUserId="30" LastActivityDate="2012-04-25T20:24:29.557" CommentCount="0" />
</posts>