<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<posts>
  <row Id="1" PostTypeId="1" CreationDate="2010-11-11T21:36:39.363" Score="10" ViewCount="190" Body="&lt;p&gt;and even more importantly what kind of questions are not pertinent here.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;I am guessing that questions related to how to implement a very specific security task would still be SO? Or am i wrong? &lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Also, are subjective questions on security like : &quot;Is a particular language more secure by default&quot; pertinent here?&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;What about administrative questions like : How to harden a Web Server configuration? Would that still be serverfault or is that now going to be discussed here?&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;" OwnerUserId="13" LastActivityDate="2011-01-09T16:39:17.917" Title="So the million dollar question...with respect to security, what kind of questions are acceptable" Tags="&lt;discussion&gt;" AnswerCount="3" CommentCount="1" FavoriteCount="2" />
  <row Id="2" PostTypeId="1" CreationDate="2010-11-11T21:36:51.327" Score="6" ViewCount="54" Body="&lt;p&gt;Are discussion question okay? I'd like to start a discussion on why XSS should be renamed Script Injection, and if there is agreement on that (I've got a few arguments), if and how we could go about promoting it.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;If the question would get shot down anyway, I wouldn't want to waste time writing down the arguments...&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;" OwnerUserId="18" LastActivityDate="2010-11-19T22:18:29.067" Title="Discussion questions" Tags="&lt;discussion&gt;" AnswerCount="2" CommentCount="0" />
  <row Id="3" PostTypeId="1" CreationDate="2010-11-11T22:17:35.133" Score="3" ViewCount="40" Body="&lt;p&gt;Three out of the 4 questions I posted, I got an error when submitting the question. However, the question was posted, resulting in me posting them twice. Also I some other posting double, so I assume they have the same problem.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;It seems it only occurs on this site.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;EDIT: it is the &quot;Oops! Something Bad Happened&quot; page. I also got it when editing this question (and yes, the edit was applied)&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;" OwnerUserId="25" LastEditorUserId="2" LastEditDate="2010-11-12T00:22:53.417" LastActivityDate="2010-11-12T00:22:53.417" Title="Errorpage when posting question - question still posted" Tags="&lt;bug&gt;&lt;status-completed&gt;" AnswerCount="0" CommentCount="1" />
  <row Id="4" PostTypeId="1" AcceptedAnswerId="5" CreationDate="2010-11-11T22:53:02.970" Score="4" ViewCount="120" Body="&lt;p&gt;Should users say thanks either in the comments or in the question itself?&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;" OwnerUserId="26" LastActivityDate="2011-01-05T17:34:40.647" Title="Should users say &quot;thanks&quot;" Tags="&lt;discussion&gt;" AnswerCount="3" CommentCount="0" />
  <row Id="5" PostTypeId="2" ParentId="4" CreationDate="2010-11-11T23:16:43.023" Score="11" Body="&lt;p&gt;I doubt it brings anything to the discussion, it only creates noise. Site will take longer to load if everyone will say thanks (yeah, not that much, but...), so I think it is not necessary.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;" OwnerUserId="62" LastActivityDate="2010-11-11T23:16:43.023" CommentCount="3" />
  <row Id="7" PostTypeId="2" ParentId="4" CreationDate="2010-11-11T23:23:11.907" Score="7" Body="&lt;p&gt;I agree with @Pawel, though if you are responding anyway it doesnt hurt to throw in another word of appreciation.&lt;br&gt;&#xA;Also, if someone took the time to write a long, comprehensive, or thoughtful answer, I think you could show your appreciation by discussing the content. Or, upvoting always works too :)&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;" OwnerUserId="33" LastActivityDate="2010-11-11T23:23:11.907" CommentCount="1" />
  <row Id="9" PostTypeId="1" CreationDate="2010-11-11T23:36:39.973" Score="1" ViewCount="165" Body="&lt;p&gt;Cuz the site is not fully consistent... Most places its &quot;Application Security&quot;, as it was in the Area51 proposal, but the logo, the domain name, and the notification email, its IT security.  &lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;My vote is to keep this AppSec focused, thats wide enough, though I might understand why @Robert would want to merge them. On the other hand, it's crystal clear that SO could not have included SF - completely different worlds...&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;" OwnerUserId="33" LastEditorUserId="33" LastEditDate="2010-11-11T23:58:17.560" LastActivityDate="2014-04-23T09:04:07.480" Title="Is the site name IT-Security, or App-Security?" Tags="&lt;discussion&gt;" AnswerCount="4" CommentCount="0" />
  <row Id="10" PostTypeId="2" ParentId="1" CreationDate="2010-11-12T00:00:01.300" Score="0" Body="&lt;p&gt;As I said &lt;a href=&quot;https://security.meta.stackexchange.com/q/9/33&quot;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;, I think this site should be focused on Application Security only, thats a wide enough topic - but not just web security.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;While I might understand why @Robert would want to merge them, it's crystal clear that SO could not have included SF - completely different worlds...&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;" OwnerUserId="33" LastEditorUserId="-1" LastEditDate="2017-03-15T15:18:12.567" LastActivityDate="2010-11-12T00:00:01.300" CommentCount="0" />
</posts>