<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<posts>
  <row Id="1" PostTypeId="1" CreationDate="2014-05-14T00:15:22.253" Score="7" ViewCount="89" Body="&lt;p&gt;One of the areas I am particularly interested in, is using systems like Lucene (ElasticSearch/Solr, etc.) to store data that is used for other computations.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Are questions about how to best index the data, structure the storage schemas, etc on topic?&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;For example, A question like:&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;blockquote&gt;&#xA;  &lt;p&gt;I use ElasticSearch, and I have a need to index multiple versions of data that are sourced from different places. Should I add a &lt;code&gt;source&lt;/code&gt; field to the data and store it all in one large index, then filter by the source for most queries, or should I have multiple indexes, and then, only when I have queries that require multiple sources for the data should I aggregate the results over the plural indexes?&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;/blockquote&gt;&#xA;" OwnerUserId="9" LastActivityDate="2014-05-14T00:43:02.760" Title="Are questions about structuring data for storage in databases/repositories/xxxx systems on topic?" Tags="&lt;discussion&gt;&lt;scope&gt;" AnswerCount="1" CommentCount="0" />
  <row Id="2" PostTypeId="2" ParentId="1" CreationDate="2014-05-14T00:43:02.760" Score="4" Body="&lt;p&gt;If it s extremely specific to a single platform and the question is more about implementation or a technology than a general data science question, I would be inclined toward saying it is off-topic. If however it can be a general question, not tied to a very specific technological product and more about reasoning than implementation, then it could be on topic.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;" OwnerUserId="51" LastActivityDate="2014-05-14T00:43:02.760" CommentCount="3" />
  <row Id="3" PostTypeId="1" AcceptedAnswerId="18" CreationDate="2014-05-14T01:58:40.517" Score="16" ViewCount="140" Body="&lt;p&gt;Why do we have a &lt;a href=&quot;https://datascience.stackexchange.com/questions/tagged/data-science&quot; class=&quot;post-tag&quot; title=&quot;show questions tagged &amp;#39;data-science&amp;#39;&quot; rel=&quot;tag&quot;&gt;data-science&lt;/a&gt; tag? It s quite obviously redundant, and it could be applied to every question on the site, so why does it exist? This seems like having a [programming] tag on &lt;a href=&quot;http://programmers.stackexchange.com&quot;&gt;Programmers&lt;/a&gt;, or a [cooking] tag on &lt;a href=&quot;http://cooking.stackexchange.com&quot;&gt;Cooking&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;" OwnerUserId="5" LastActivityDate="2014-05-14T16:28:07.533" Title="What is the point of the [data-science] tag?" Tags="&lt;discussion&gt;&lt;tags&gt;" AnswerCount="2" CommentCount="0" />
  <row Id="4" PostTypeId="2" ParentId="3" CreationDate="2014-05-14T05:38:27.333" Score="2" Body="&lt;p&gt;The tag is obviously redundant. But this is typical for all SE sites. &lt;/p&gt;&#xA;" OwnerUserId="97" LastActivityDate="2014-05-14T05:38:27.333" CommentCount="1" />
  <row Id="5" PostTypeId="1" CreationDate="2014-05-14T07:51:39.190" Score="4" ViewCount="74" Body="&lt;h2&gt;Should we implement a &lt;a href=&quot;https://stats.stackexchange.com/tags/self-study/info&quot;&gt;[self-study]&lt;/a&gt; tag in a similar way to stats.SE?&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;I think that curious people will be drawn to this site to find out more about big-data in general.  &lt;strong&gt;My question is mainly two-fold:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;ol&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;While I think that &quot;How do I learn more&quot; is too broad and should be flagged as such, there may be ways to specifically refine the question or narrow the scope so that the question becomes answerable (in a way that isn t overly opinion-based). Perhaps such a question can be limited to a specific discipline?&lt;a href=&quot;https://datascience.stackexchange.com/questions/tagged/scope&quot; class=&quot;post-tag&quot; title=&quot;show questions tagged &amp;#39;scope&amp;#39;&quot; rel=&quot;tag&quot;&gt;scope&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;We may field questions that don t properly belong in either a programming, statistics, or super-user SE.  And if these questions are for coursework, is there any utility for our community to have this tag (without it solely being an academic honesty concern for the OP)? &lt;a href=&quot;https://datascience.stackexchange.com/questions/tagged/discussion&quot; class=&quot;post-tag&quot; title=&quot;show questions tagged &amp;#39;discussion&amp;#39;&quot; rel=&quot;tag&quot;&gt;discussion&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ol&gt;&#xA;" OwnerUserId="53" LastEditorUserId="-1" LastEditDate="2017-04-13T12:44:19.770" LastActivityDate="2014-05-14T07:51:39.190" Title="Should we adopt a [self-study] tag like stats.SE in scope and approach?" Tags="&lt;discussion&gt;&lt;tags&gt;&lt;scope&gt;" AnswerCount="0" CommentCount="1" />
  <row Id="6" PostTypeId="1" CreationDate="2014-05-14T08:11:02.157" Score="36" ViewCount="261" Body="&lt;p&gt;Like on math.stackexchange, where (for example) I can type for square root of 2?&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;If we want to be able to quote equations from data science research papers, this seems pretty essential.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;" OwnerUserId="14" LastEditorUserId="1" LastEditDate="2014-12-12T20:52:50.630" LastActivityDate="2014-12-12T20:57:19.903" Title="Can we get TeX support?" Tags="&lt;feature-request&gt;&lt;status-completed&gt;" AnswerCount="6" CommentCount="3" FavoriteCount="3" />
  <row Id="7" PostTypeId="1" AcceptedAnswerId="14" CreationDate="2014-05-14T08:57:41.947" Score="3" ViewCount="88" Body="&lt;h2&gt;Are all ethical considerations for the data scientist already subsumed by a blend of other professional disciplines and &lt;a href=&quot;https://security.stackexchange.com/questions/tagged/ethics&quot;&gt;Information Security&lt;/a&gt; (INFOSEC)?&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;I can see that many ethical dilemmas will be related to INFOSEC or corporate espionage and data privacy.  While ethical questions could be pushed off to other sites, is there a place for those questions here?  Does the exploitation of big data create for us any professional responsibility?&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;I would argue that we do have professional responsibilities&lt;/strong&gt;, but many of those have to do with our concepts of &lt;em&gt;privacy&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;ownership&lt;/em&gt; especially information ownership, and &lt;em&gt;public welfare&lt;/em&gt;.  And since these concepts are highly dependent upon our cultural upbringing, I wanted to invite discussion on this topic to expose those things that myself and others may be taking for granted because of uncritical cultural biases.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;If we do have our own professional code of ethics (even if in the making), where do these unique responsibilities and concerns originate from?&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;If our concerns are not terribly unique, then is there something remarkable in the collection of concerns that occur regularly for data scientists that warrants expounding or codifying?&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;h2&gt;A question of scope&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;If there are ethical considerations that are unique or are more than just the sum of other disciplines, then I would propose that questions about ethics are on-topic for this site.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;If questions about {ethics} is on-topic, does it need its own tag?  And/or should we adjust the site s &lt;em&gt;help&lt;/em&gt; page?&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;However, if the prevailing opinion is that there is nothing really specific to the ethics of data science that warrants separate treatment - then we can determine such posts to be off-topic.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;" OwnerUserId="53" LastEditorUserId="-1" LastEditDate="2017-03-17T10:46:11.373" LastActivityDate="2014-06-18T19:35:14.720" Title="Are ethical considerations for the data scientist within scope? Is {ethics} on topic?" Tags="&lt;discussion&gt;&lt;scope&gt;" AnswerCount="2" CommentCount="2" />
  <row Id="8" PostTypeId="1" CreationDate="2014-05-14T09:50:33.417" Score="4" ViewCount="55" Body="&lt;p&gt;Certain languages such as R and libraries/platforms such as Hadoop are used almost exclusively in data science. Should programming or configuration based questions for such languages, databases, libraries be on-topic?&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;" OwnerUserId="62" LastActivityDate="2014-05-14T14:43:37.683" Title="Are questions about languages, libraries and databases on-topic?" Tags="&lt;discussion&gt;&lt;scope&gt;" AnswerCount="1" CommentCount="0" />
  <row Id="9" PostTypeId="1" CreationDate="2014-05-14T10:07:28.997" Score="11" ViewCount="395" Body="&lt;p&gt;I feel it would be interesting to get to know other each other and why you are participating on this beta. As data science is fairly new, knowing about each other s background would provide us a better picture of the community. &lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Post your responses as answers to this question. Please try to mention:&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Who are you?&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;What do you do?&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;What interests you in Data Science? What got you started?&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Why are you on this site?&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;So, welcome to Data Science Stack Exchange! Go ahead and introduce yourselves!&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;" OwnerUserId="62" LastEditorUserId="62" LastEditDate="2014-06-10T12:15:19.177" LastActivityDate="2014-12-27T21:26:13.820" Title="Who are you and why are you here?" Tags="&lt;discussion&gt;&lt;community&gt;" AnswerCount="13" CommentCount="0" />
  <row Id="10" PostTypeId="2" ParentId="6" CreationDate="2014-05-14T10:25:32.557" Score="18" Body="&lt;p&gt;I would say that it is a must. Suppose that one is asking how to implement ridge linear regression, using only plain text is scary even to think about it.   &lt;/p&gt;&#xA;" OwnerUserId="108" LastActivityDate="2014-05-14T10:25:32.557" CommentCount="0" />
</posts>