<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<posts>
  <row Id="1" PostTypeId="1" AcceptedAnswerId="366" CreationDate="2014-04-15T18:11:01.930" Score="21" ViewCount="472" Body="&lt;p&gt;The atmosphere is a highly dynamical system, and exhibits many chaotical features.  An operational weather forecasting model tries to model an initial value problem, in fact one of the most famous examples of a chaotic system.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Climate&lt;/em&gt; however, is the statistics of the behaviour of the atmosphere over a long period of time.  It is not an initial value problem; it is a boundary value problem.  Whereas small changes in initial values can imply large changes in behaviour over time, can there be any similar behaviour in climate?&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;For example, we force a climate model with prescribed atmospheric constituents, coastlines, orbital characteristics, etc.  Can a &lt;em&gt;small&lt;/em&gt; change in any of those boundary values lead to a climate exbiting a different state?  Or, similarly, can, in the context of natural variability only, the climate suddenly switch to a very different state?&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;" OwnerUserId="6" LastActivityDate="2014-04-20T15:07:33.163" Title="Is climate chaotic?" Tags="&lt;climate&gt;&lt;atmosphere&gt;&lt;chaos&gt;" AnswerCount="2" CommentCount="6" FavoriteCount="5" />
  <row Id="2" PostTypeId="1" AcceptedAnswerId="2962" CreationDate="2014-04-15T18:21:53.510" Score="14" ViewCount="127" Body="&lt;p&gt;In-situ measurements in deep convective systems, tropical cyclones, etc., are difficult to perform.  Few if any people would like to fly a small aircraft close to its core, and radiosondes or larger balloons would be ripped to pieces.  Even flying high above the top of such a system may not be a pleasant idea.  However, with unmanned aerial vehicles (UAVs or drones), perhaps higher risks can be taken than with manned aircraft.  And whereas radiosondes cannot be launched, dropsondes should not be a problem.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Are there any projects, either operationally or for research purposes, that involve dropping sondes from UAVs flying above deep convective systems, in order to measure profiles of pressure, temperature, as well as cloud and precipitation properties?&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;" OwnerUserId="6" LastEditorUserId="64" LastEditDate="2014-12-05T19:02:37.117" LastActivityDate="2014-12-05T19:02:37.117" Title="Have there been any attempts to measure profiles through deep convective systems using dropsondes?" Tags="&lt;meteorology&gt;&lt;atmosphere&gt;&lt;measurements&gt;&lt;storms&gt;" AnswerCount="1" CommentCount="6" FavoriteCount="2" />
  <row Id="3" PostTypeId="1" AcceptedAnswerId="140" CreationDate="2014-04-15T18:25:40.903" Score="9" ViewCount="91" Body="&lt;p&gt;Remote sounding of the atmosphere is a well-established method used extensively used extensively for operational weather forecasting and scientific research.  Active or passive instruments carried on satellites (or aircraft) can measure profiles of temperature, pressure, trace gases, and particulate matter.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Is anything similar possible for a ship sailing on the ocean?  What methods exist, in theory and in practice, to remotely sense a profile of temperature, density, salinity, etc., from the ocean floor to the ship?  Or can such profiles only be obtained in-situ?&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;" OwnerUserId="6" LastActivityDate="2014-04-16T22:27:56.657" Title="What methods exist for remote profiling of oceanic columns?" Tags="&lt;measurements&gt;&lt;ocean&gt;&lt;remote-sensing&gt;" AnswerCount="1" CommentCount="0" />
  <row Id="4" PostTypeId="1" CreationDate="2014-04-15T18:56:43.193" Score="8" ViewCount="93" Body="&lt;p&gt;The &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Virtual_temperature&quot;&gt;virtual temperature&lt;/a&gt; is a pseudo-temperature taking into account water vapour in the atmosphere in such a way, that the resulting quantity can be used with the ideal gas law and the molar mass for dry air.  Although the most significant in the troposphere, water vapour is not the only trace gas for which the concentration varies through the atmosphere.  Are there any similarly defined pseudo-temperatures, taking into account varying volume mixing ratios for other trace gases?&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;" OwnerUserId="6" LastEditorUserId="124" LastEditDate="2014-04-30T16:00:11.327" LastActivityDate="2014-04-30T16:00:11.327" Title="Are there any quantities defined analogically to the virtual temperature, but for other gases?" Tags="&lt;atmosphere&gt;&lt;meteorology&gt;" AnswerCount="1" CommentCount="2" />
  <row Id="5" PostTypeId="1" CreationDate="2014-04-15T19:10:00.560" Score="9" ViewCount="126" Body="&lt;p&gt;So we know that surface air temperatures are warmer during El Niño events (which implies that there is more heat in the atmosphere, although maybe it s possible that it also means there s less heat in the oceans?).&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;I m wondering... though.. Could this simply mean that the land surface emits more longwave radiation out into space during periods of El Niño. &lt;/p&gt;&#xA;" OwnerUserId="10" LastEditorUserId="111" LastEditDate="2014-12-21T21:52:04.513" LastActivityDate="2014-12-21T21:53:28.560" Title="Does El Niño increase the amount of heat that escapes into space, or does it increase the amount of heat trapped on Earth?" Tags="&lt;atmosphere&gt;&lt;enso&gt;" AnswerCount="1" CommentCount="0" />
  <row Id="6" PostTypeId="1" CreationDate="2014-04-15T19:15:52.640" Score="12" ViewCount="5853" Body="&lt;p&gt;Do cirrus clouds in the upper troposphere move faster than cumulus and stratus clouds in the lower atmosphere?&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;What about clouds associated with extratropical systems, compared with clouds in the tropics?&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;" OwnerUserId="10" LastEditorUserId="10681" LastEditDate="2017-09-20T20:01:20.770" LastActivityDate="2017-09-25T14:47:19.227" Title="What determines how fast clouds move?" Tags="&lt;meteorology&gt;&lt;atmosphere&gt;&lt;clouds&gt;" AnswerCount="2" CommentCount="1" />
  <row Id="7" PostTypeId="1" CreationDate="2014-04-15T19:21:12.483" Score="17" ViewCount="908" Body="&lt;p&gt;So &lt;a href=&quot;http://dspace.mit.edu/openaccess-disseminate/1721.1/52333&quot;&gt;Enderton and Marshall&lt;/a&gt; (2009) wrote an interesting paper on the ocean circulation of various aquaplanets covered with certain terrain: e.g. an aquaplanet with a small ridge of land that ranged from North Pole to South Pole, and studied the effects it had on the ocean circulation.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;I m curious: Has anyone ever applied this type of analysis to a Pangaea-like planet?&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;" OwnerUserId="10" LastEditorUserId="56" LastEditDate="2014-04-16T02:44:56.993" LastActivityDate="2014-04-16T02:44:56.993" Title="What was the ocean circulation like during the time of Pangaea?" Tags="&lt;ocean&gt;&lt;thermohaline-circulation&gt;&lt;oceanography&gt;&lt;geochronology&gt;" AnswerCount="1" CommentCount="0" />
  <row Id="8" PostTypeId="1" AcceptedAnswerId="1070" CreationDate="2014-04-15T19:25:48.243" Score="15" ViewCount="365" Body="&lt;p&gt;Figure 1.12 from the &lt;a href=&quot;http://ipcc.ch/report/ar5/wg1/&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow noreferrer&quot;&gt;IPCC AR5 WG1 report&lt;/a&gt; (reproduced below) illustrates the different instruments that have been used for weather forecasting.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Most of the methods have been in continuous use since their inception, except one: kites were used, but later disbanded.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Why is this so?  &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.ctie.monash.edu.au/hargrave/kites_and_meterology.html&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow noreferrer&quot;&gt;This Monash university article from 1999&lt;/a&gt; makes the point that they are superseded by radiosondes and aircraft.  However, atmospheric measurements on aircraft are very expensive and mainly used for research as opposed to operational weather forecasting; and, unlike weather kites, they do not (normally) fly in the boundary layer¹.  Radiosondes are only launched once or twice per 24 hours per location.  Passive (operational) space-borne measurements have a lower vertical resolution, in particular near the boundary layer.  I imagine that kites should provide a low-cost, high-resolution (both temporally and vertically) profile of the boundary layer.  Why is it they are not really used operationally anymore?&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://i.stack.imgur.com/VQ0TX.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;IPCC AR5 WG1 Figure 1.12&quot;&gt;&#xA;&lt;sup&gt;&#xA;&lt;br /&gt;Figure 1.12 | Development of capabilities of observations. Top: Changes in the mix and increasing diversity of observations over time create challenges for a consistent climate record (adapted from Brönnimann et al., 2008). Bottom left: First year of temperature data in Global Historical Climatology Network (GHCN) daily database (available at &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.ncdc.noaa.gov/oa/climate/ghcn-daily/&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow noreferrer&quot;&gt;http://www.ncdc.noaa.gov/oa/climate/ghcn-daily/&lt;/a&gt;; Menne et al., 2012). Bottom right: Number of satellite instruments from which data have been assimilated in the European Centre for Medium-Range Weather Forecasts production streams for each year from 1996 to 2010. This figure is used as an example to demonstrate the fivefold increase in the usage of satellite data over this time period.  Figure reference: &lt;em&gt;Cubasch, U., D. Wuebbles, D. Chen, M.C. Facchini, D. Frame, N. Mahowald and J.-G. Winther, 2013: Introduction. In: Climate Change 2013: The Physical Science Basis. Contribution of Working Group I to the Fifth Assessment Report of the Intergovernmental Panel on Climate Change [Stocker, T.F., D. Qin, G.-K. Plattner, M. Tignor, S.K. Allen, J. Boschung, A. Nauels, Y. Xia, V. Bex and P.M. Midgley (eds.)]. Cambridge University Press, Cambridge, United Kingdom and New York, NY, USA.&lt;/em&gt;&#xA;&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;hr&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;¹&lt;sup&gt;Research aircraft sometimes do.  Flying in a full-sized jet 20 metre above the ocean surface is an interesting experience!&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;" OwnerUserId="6" LastEditorUserId="6" LastEditDate="2014-05-08T14:48:14.163" LastActivityDate="2016-07-14T01:20:59.017" Title="Why are weather kites no longer used (much) operationally?" Tags="&lt;measurements&gt;&lt;weather&gt;" AnswerCount="1" CommentCount="10" FavoriteCount="3" />
  <row Id="9" PostTypeId="1" CreationDate="2014-04-15T19:27:53.613" Score="7" ViewCount="145" Body="&lt;p&gt;So as we know, climate change is associated with increased radiation flux into the Earth. In other words, the sum of (incoming shortwave radiation) - (outgoing longwave radiation) [which I will call net flux] is greater than 0.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;I m just curious though - how have all of these fluxes changed over the last 20 years? Has net flux been constantly positive over the last 20-30 years? Is it changed by El Niño? Have we seen any changes in the flux associated with the recent &quot;slowdown&quot; in global warming?&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;" OwnerUserId="10" LastEditorUserId="111" LastEditDate="2014-12-21T21:40:25.713" LastActivityDate="2014-12-21T21:40:25.713" Title="How have levels of outgoing longwave and incoming shortwave radiation changed over the last 20-30 years?" Tags="&lt;climate&gt;" AnswerCount="1" CommentCount="1" />
  <row Id="10" PostTypeId="2" ParentId="6" CreationDate="2014-04-15T19:28:51.787" Score="14" Body="&lt;p&gt;Cloud particles are suspended in air, and their movement is governed by:&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Wind; whichever way the wind blows, the clouds go (with some exceptions such as lenticular clouds; thanks &lt;a href=&quot;https://earthscience.stackexchange.com/questions/6/what-determines-how-fast-clouds-move/10?noredirect=1#comment22564_10&quot;&gt;jamesqf comment&lt;/a&gt;).  The wind is often &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Jet_stream&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow noreferrer&quot;&gt;strongest in the upper troposphere&lt;/a&gt; (there are no clouds in the upper atmosphere), so upper tropospheric clouds will move faster than near-surface clouds.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Convection: strong updrafts will force particles upward, as will forced convection by wind reaching obstacles&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Particle size: larger particles are more likely to fall down.  Note that &quot;fall down&quot; may be used either relative to the surrounding air, or relative to the ground (i.e. precipitation that may or may not reach the ground).&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;So the type of cloud is indirectly relevant: different cloud types are associated with different particle sizes, are to a larger or smaller degree the consequence of convection, and are more or less likely to contain precipitation-sized particles.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;" OwnerUserId="6" LastEditorUserId="6" LastEditDate="2017-09-25T14:47:19.227" LastActivityDate="2017-09-25T14:47:19.227" CommentCount="2" />
</posts>