<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<posts>
  <row Id="1" PostTypeId="1" AcceptedAnswerId="2" CreationDate="2015-01-20T18:35:59.493" Score="28" ViewCount="3717" Body="&lt;p&gt;Is it possible to &quot;pump&quot; a powder the same way liquids can be pumped?&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;If so, what are the challenges? If not, what are some alternatives?&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;" OwnerUserId="9" LastEditorUserId="148" LastEditDate="2015-01-21T08:28:32.950" LastActivityDate="2016-06-28T09:12:52.693" Title="Is it possible to &quot;pump&quot; a powder?" Tags="&lt;pumps&gt;&lt;liquid&gt;&lt;fluid-mechanics&gt;" AnswerCount="7" CommentCount="2" FavoriteCount="3" />
  <row Id="2" PostTypeId="2" ParentId="1" CreationDate="2015-01-20T18:41:00.530" Score="25" Body="&lt;p&gt;I believe it s termed &quot;injecting&quot; not &quot;pumping&quot; but yes, it s certainly possible.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Coal fired electric power plants grind the coal to a very fine dust and then blow the dust into the central burner.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.netl.doe.gov/File%20Library/Research/Coal/major%20demonstrations/cctdp/Round3/bethstl.pdf&quot;&gt;This particular article&lt;/a&gt; is a summary of some DOE research for a Blast Furnace Granulated Coal Injection System Demonstration Project.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;And &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.nfpa.org/~/media/Files/Research/Research%20Foundation/foundation%20proceedings/david_snell.pdf&quot;&gt;this article&lt;/a&gt; discusses some of the hazards from a National Fire Protection Association perspective.  Coal dust having the particular dangerous property of being explosive and all that...&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;As far as specifics regarding danger, I suspect it will vary depending upon the material(s) involved in the powder.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;" OwnerUserId="16" LastActivityDate="2015-01-20T18:41:00.530" CommentCount="5" />
  <row Id="3" PostTypeId="1" CreationDate="2015-01-20T18:41:20.310" Score="9" ViewCount="702" Body="&lt;p&gt;What would be the best type of steel to specify? Would a heavy galvanization suffice?&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Are there specialty paints/coatings available for this particular application? If so, how long do they last?&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;" OwnerUserId="3" LastEditorUserId="33" LastEditDate="2015-10-18T18:40:48.110" LastActivityDate="2015-10-18T18:40:48.110" Title="What kind of protection should I give structural steel in a natatorium (swiming pool) environment?" Tags="&lt;steel&gt;&lt;structures&gt;&lt;corrosion&gt;" AnswerCount="3" CommentCount="3" FavoriteCount="0" />
  <row Id="4" PostTypeId="1" AcceptedAnswerId="248" CreationDate="2015-01-20T18:41:51.527" Score="5" ViewCount="103" Body="&lt;p&gt;I think, actually the first row is needed is a &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Barometric_formula&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;barometric height formula&lt;/a&gt; for the mix of gases.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The main problem I can see, the curves describing the minimal energy (kinetic + gravitational/centrifugal) won t be any more a simple derivative, but a functional equation.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;I think, this or similar equations could be useful in very separate areas (isotope separation, estimating high atmosphere components of planets, etc.) Despite I couldn t find anything with google about this.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;So, the question is: we have a high gas mixture in constant g gravity and T temperature. We known the p1, p2, ... partial pressures of the gases on the h=0. Of course we know every relevant constants of the gases, too. What is their minimal-energy, isothermic, height-dependent partial pressure function pn(h)?&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;" OwnerUserId="9" LastEditorUserId="160" LastEditDate="2015-02-14T15:04:27.127" LastActivityDate="2015-02-14T15:04:27.127" Title="Multi-gas barometric height formula in isotope separation devices?" Tags="&lt;pressure&gt;&lt;gas&gt;&lt;nuclear-technology&gt;" AnswerCount="1" CommentCount="4" />
  <row Id="6" PostTypeId="1" AcceptedAnswerId="8" CreationDate="2015-01-20T19:49:53.683" Score="11" ViewCount="642" Body="&lt;p&gt;The United States have different rules about exactly how one obtains an engineering license, but the general process is the FE exam, a few years of work, and the PE exam. Suppose one then wishes to practice engineering in Germany. What are the legal requirements for doing so?&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;" OwnerUserId="18" LastActivityDate="2015-01-21T18:46:54.050" Title="What is the process of transferring an engineering license from the United States to Germany?" Tags="&lt;licensure&gt;&lt;international&gt;" AnswerCount="2" CommentCount="4" />
  <row Id="8" PostTypeId="2" ParentId="6" CreationDate="2015-01-20T20:27:48.367" Score="7" Body="&lt;p&gt;Unlike within the &lt;a href=&quot;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Regulation_and_licensure_in_engineering&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;United States and the PE license&lt;/a&gt;, it doesn t appear that it s possible to receive an &lt;a href=&quot;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/European_Engineer&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;EUR ING&lt;/a&gt; license by &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.nspe.org/resources/licensure/resources/licensure-comity&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;direct comity&lt;/a&gt;.  EU Engineering licensing is handled by &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.feani.org/site/index.php&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;FEANI&lt;/a&gt;, and on their &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.feani.org/site/index.php?id=261&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;EUR ING&lt;/a&gt; page they state: &lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;blockquote&gt;&#xA;  &lt;p&gt;Application is open only to individuals if they are members of an engineering association represented in FEANI through a National Member&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;/blockquote&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;But it may be possible to join one of the &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.feani.org/site/index.php?id=57&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;German FEANI members&lt;/a&gt; and see if they can support a reciprocity or comity process.&lt;sup&gt;1&lt;/sup&gt;  &lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;sup&gt;1&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;sub&gt;There are other member organization in other countries, but your question specifically mentioned Germany.&lt;/sub&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;hr&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Digging a bit deeper, it does appear that there may be limited cases where an EUR ING will be awarded based upon sufficient experience as a professional engineer.  Take a look through the &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.feani.org/site/index.php?eID=tx_nawsecuredl&amp;amp;u=0&amp;amp;file=fileadmin/PDF_Documents/EUR_ING_Tittle/Guide_to_the_Register_FINAL_approved_GA_2013.pdf&amp;amp;t=1421941885&amp;amp;hash=f78dd0dcf1b44b41a9cc45e17cc6500d1f436621&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;FEANI EUR ING guide&lt;/a&gt;, in particular Section 5 which details the minimum requirements.  Most of the cases cover qualifications based upon an education received within an FEANI member country.  Section 5.4b deals with special circumstances and provides the potential pathway that you could receive an EUR ING license.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;blockquote&gt;&#xA;  &lt;p&gt;Nevertheless it is possible to consider such alternative routes. Very strict procedures, however, have then to be followed, (see 7.1), and the applicant must have at least 15 years of Professional Engineering Experience recognized by FEANI.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;/blockquote&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;So it does appear to be possible, but again, it s not as simple as the comity process within the United States.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;" OwnerUserId="16" LastEditorUserId="16" LastEditDate="2015-01-21T18:46:54.050" LastActivityDate="2015-01-21T18:46:54.050" CommentCount="0" />
  <row Id="9" PostTypeId="1" CreationDate="2015-01-20T20:31:25.093" Score="12" ViewCount="863" Body="&lt;p&gt;I am currently having an issue where features of my machined parts are warping. I am using Alloy 7050 Type I and Type III in this particular case. Using a feeler gauge and a certified, calibrated granite slab, I am getting out-of-flatness measurements up to .009, which is significantly out of tolerance relative to my requirements.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;I have decided to construct a statistically-designed experiment (&lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Design_of_experiments#Experimental_designs_after_Fisher&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;design of experiments&lt;/a&gt;) to find which specific factors are playing a role, but I want to ensure that I am including all of the factors which may contribute.  I don t want to lead the conversation too much by posting what I already listed, but I am looking for others  opinions on what might cause this kind of warping/deflection.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;" OwnerUserId="35" LastEditorUserId="368" LastEditDate="2015-04-27T16:25:03.123" LastActivityDate="2016-08-05T22:48:57.023" Title="In aluminum machining, what are the most common factors that might cause a machined component to have warping issues?" Tags="&lt;mechanical-engineering&gt;&lt;machining&gt;&lt;aluminum&gt;&lt;quality-engineering&gt;" AnswerCount="3" CommentCount="4" />
  <row Id="10" PostTypeId="1" CreationDate="2015-01-20T21:19:03.447" Score="3" ViewCount="183" Body="&lt;p&gt;I am currently considering turning my fascination with magnets into a diy activity. &lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;How feasible is it for a hobbyist to construct a working model of a &lt;a href=&quot;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Maglev&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;maglev&lt;/a&gt; device?&#xA;I m looking to build something  really small for now,just a demonstrative prototype that can hover over a surface.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;I m looking for a rough idea of cost, time and materials. Is it something that can be attempted while working a full time job?&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Does anyone know of any good starting points in terms of literature? &lt;/p&gt;&#xA;" OwnerUserId="42" LastEditorUserId="13974" LastEditDate="2017-12-02T15:58:39.070" LastActivityDate="2017-12-02T15:58:39.070" Title="Magnetic levitation" Tags="&lt;electrical-engineering&gt;&lt;magnets&gt;&lt;electromagnetism&gt;&lt;propulsion&gt;&lt;linear-motors&gt;" AnswerCount="1" CommentCount="5" FavoriteCount="0" ClosedDate="2015-01-21T23:07:02.393" />
</posts>