<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<posts>
  <row Id="1" PostTypeId="1" AcceptedAnswerId="9" CreationDate="2011-06-08T18:35:50.450" Score="26" ViewCount="64037" Body="&lt;p&gt;Which side of a house will get the most sunlight?  Articles on the internet seem to have conflicting answers. Is this because it is dependent on location?&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;" OwnerUserId="9" LastEditorUserId="109" LastEditDate="2011-07-25T05:14:51.753" LastActivityDate="2016-08-02T14:16:20.200" Title="Which side of a house will get the most sunlight?" Tags="&lt;houseplants&gt;&lt;sunlight&gt;" AnswerCount="5" CommentCount="1" FavoriteCount="2" />
  <row Id="2" PostTypeId="1" AcceptedAnswerId="64" CreationDate="2011-06-08T18:37:12.493" Score="26" ViewCount="1717" Body="&lt;p&gt;When I try to grow &quot;upside-down&quot; tomatoes, they always curve back up towards the sun and eventually break, causing massive damage.  Could I be doing something wrong, or is there a way to avoid this?&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;" OwnerUserId="11" LastEditorUserId="109" LastEditDate="2011-07-06T19:04:30.607" LastActivityDate="2013-05-21T13:11:22.700" Title="Why do my upside-down tomato plants curve up and break?" Tags="&lt;tomatoes&gt;" AnswerCount="2" CommentCount="2" FavoriteCount="1" />
  <row Id="3" PostTypeId="1" AcceptedAnswerId="29" CreationDate="2011-06-08T18:37:45.593" Score="32" ViewCount="2559" Body="&lt;p&gt;I've got what I think is a cedar tree in my backyard that is missing most of its bark on one side from the ground to about 4' up. (Thanks to my puppy who is a shredding machine.) The branches next to the bare area of the trunk are slowly turning brown and dying. Is there any way to revive the tree and minimize the damage? Should I prune off branches that appear to be mostly dead?&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Also, on the topic of preventative action: Are there products that successfully keep animals (dogs in my case) away from trees and shrubs?&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;" OwnerUserId="6" LastEditorUserId="109" LastEditDate="2011-07-17T14:35:42.393" LastActivityDate="2016-04-25T20:02:23.973" Title="How can I revive a tree that's been stripped of bark?" Tags="&lt;trees&gt;&lt;tree-care&gt;" AnswerCount="3" CommentCount="0" />
  <row Id="4" PostTypeId="1" AcceptedAnswerId="11" CreationDate="2011-06-08T18:37:53.583" Score="29" ViewCount="308" Body="&lt;p&gt;I've got a big, lovely rhubarb plant in my yard which I'd hoped to be able to harvest a few different times over the course of a summer. How should I harvest my rhubarb to encourage it to regrow quickly? Should I cut it off near the base, pull it up from the root, or something else? Should I harvest it all at once, or should I leave some of the stalks in place?&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;" OwnerUserId="20" LastEditorUserId="7305" LastEditDate="2016-02-19T00:47:35.537" LastActivityDate="2016-02-19T07:50:30.103" Title="What's the most effective way to harvest rhubarb?" Tags="&lt;rhubarb&gt;&lt;vegetables&gt;&lt;harvesting&gt;" AnswerCount="3" CommentCount="1" FavoriteCount="1" />
  <row Id="5" PostTypeId="2" ParentId="1" CreationDate="2011-06-08T18:38:53.847" Score="8" Body="&lt;p&gt;This question depends on context.  &lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;I could say the north side but for all I know the north side of your house has no windows.  &lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;It also depends on geographic location.  Where does the sun rise/set.  &lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Do you have any trees/objects near your house that would obstruct light?  &lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;There are varying factors here to say the least.  &lt;/p&gt;&#xA;" OwnerUserId="31" LastEditorUserId="31" LastEditDate="2011-06-08T19:09:41.273" LastActivityDate="2011-06-08T19:09:41.273" CommentCount="3" />
  <row Id="6" PostTypeId="1" CreationDate="2011-06-08T18:39:09.920" Score="26" ViewCount="4069" Body="&lt;p&gt;My town recently took down a large 80 year old maple tree that sat on the south side of my house.  Unfortunately that tree provided much-needed shade and now I have already noticed very high temperatures in my  house.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;I would like to plant a replacement tree - but of course it will take a while to grow.  I have been contemplating a tulip tree, but perhaps there is a better, fast growing tree.  &lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;I spoke with the town arborist - he said they would replace it - but likely with a tree that would grow no more than 12 feet high.  He scoffed at my mention of a Tulip tree - but his priorities are not the same as mine - he is concerned for the road asphalt and the power lines - whereas I want my cooling effect.  (I would not plant this on the town right-of-way where the other tree was removed - it would be further on my property away form power and the road)&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;EDIT&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;I did &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.ext.colostate.edu/pubs/garden/07419.html&quot;&gt;find this&lt;/a&gt; but am not sure what they mean by &quot;fast&quot;.  I do have a tulip tree in another part of my property that grows fast, but nothing to compare it to.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;This &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.english-gardening.com/Plants/fast_growing_tree.htm&quot;&gt;site seems to be good&lt;/a&gt; - I might go with a pecan because it has value other than shade.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;" OwnerUserId="23" LastEditorUserId="23" LastEditDate="2011-06-08T18:58:27.547" LastActivityDate="2015-12-16T00:01:12.070" Title="What is a fast-growing deciduous tree for shading house in summer? (Long Island, NY)" Tags="&lt;trees&gt;&lt;shade&gt;" AnswerCount="5" CommentCount="6" FavoriteCount="2" />
  <row Id="7" PostTypeId="1" AcceptedAnswerId="296" CreationDate="2011-06-08T18:39:33.863" Score="17" ViewCount="305" Body="&lt;p&gt;I read in &lt;a href=&quot;http://rads.stackoverflow.com/amzn/click/1580170269&quot;&gt;Tips for the Lazy Gardener&lt;/a&gt; that gardens in drier parts of Africa can be triple dug (as opposed to double dug, or as I prefer, barely dug) which will somehow absorb more water during the rainy season and store it for the remainder of the growing season.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;What conditions would prompt a person, not living in a desert or savannah, to triple dig their garden? &lt;/p&gt;&#xA;" OwnerUserId="10" LastEditorUserId="10" LastEditDate="2011-07-25T19:21:13.780" LastActivityDate="2011-07-25T19:21:13.780" Title="Is triple digging worth the backache in temperate biomes?" Tags="&lt;soil&gt;" AnswerCount="1" CommentCount="1" />
  <row Id="8" PostTypeId="1" AcceptedAnswerId="19" CreationDate="2011-06-08T18:39:39.290" Score="26" ViewCount="1147" Body="&lt;p&gt;We have a flat (apartment) with no garden, but would love to grow root vegetables such as potatoes and carrots. Is it possible to grow these in a pot, container or grow-bag, or do they need too much depth for this?&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;If it is possible, what containers would be recommended? I assume deep pots - but would those get enough drainage?&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;" OwnerUserId="24" LastEditorUserId="109" LastEditDate="2011-09-03T04:36:40.910" LastActivityDate="2015-03-08T21:30:05.007" Title="How do I grow root vegetables in pots/grow-bags?" Tags="&lt;vegetables&gt;&lt;containers&gt;&lt;root-vegetables&gt;" AnswerCount="4" CommentCount="1" FavoriteCount="4" />
  <row Id="9" PostTypeId="2" ParentId="1" CreationDate="2011-06-08T18:39:49.137" Score="28" Body="&lt;p&gt;In general, it depends on your location. In the northern hemisphere, the south side gets the bulk of the sun, because the sun is in that half of the sky. &lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;But if you are on a hill, or have a hill to the east or west, it can significantly shorten your solar 'day'.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Additionally, if you are in an area that tends to get morning fog, east-facing will get less effective sun than west-facing, because by afternoon the sun will have burned off the fog.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Finally, elevation matters. Higher floors will get more sun because they &quot;see&quot; more of the sky.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;So in general, the south-west of the house will get the most sun, with upper floors receiving more than lower floors.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;" OwnerUserId="32" LastActivityDate="2011-06-08T18:39:49.137" CommentCount="1" />
  <row Id="10" PostTypeId="1" CreationDate="2011-06-08T18:40:18.730" Score="19" ViewCount="5302" Body="&lt;p&gt;How often should I fertilize my lawn? Should I follow a certain schedule? I have heard of people fertilizing on around holidays [US: Easter (sometime in April), Memorial day (last week of May), fourth of July, Labor day (first week of September)].  &lt;/p&gt;&#xA;" OwnerUserId="30" LastEditorUserId="109" LastEditDate="2011-09-03T04:34:46.607" LastActivityDate="2011-09-03T04:34:46.607" Title="How often should I fertilize my lawn?" Tags="&lt;lawn&gt;&lt;grass&gt;&lt;fertilizer&gt;" AnswerCount="3" CommentCount="2" FavoriteCount="1" />
</posts>