<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<posts>
  <row Id="2" PostTypeId="1" AcceptedAnswerId="14" CreationDate="2015-03-31T19:00:01.793" Score="33" ViewCount="15477" Body="&lt;p&gt;The following tooth cracks are noticeable when a torch is shining on them (without the torch, they aren t visible).  Are they serious?  How viable are the teeth, and might they need to be replaced with false teeth in the near future?  There is no pain experienced, but they seem to look quite bad:&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://i.stack.imgur.com/2sgis.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Teeth 1&quot;&gt;&#xA;&lt;img src=&quot;https://i.stack.imgur.com/k3R8j.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Teeth 2&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;" OwnerUserId="8" LastEditorUserId="8" LastEditDate="2015-03-31T19:33:14.567" LastActivityDate="2015-04-08T01:00:04.903" Title="What are these lines in teeth?" Tags="&lt;dentistry&gt;" AnswerCount="1" CommentCount="1" FavoriteCount="3" />
  <row Id="3" PostTypeId="1" CreationDate="2015-03-31T19:06:32.503" Score="13" ViewCount="147" Body="&lt;p&gt;(By  fortified , I refer to this definition: &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.oxforddictionaries.com/definition/english/fortify?q=fortified&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow noreferrer&quot;&gt;increase the nutritive value of (food) by adding vitamins&lt;/a&gt;.)&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Are there any differences between calcium supplements (as pills or tablets), and foods fortified with calcium (e.g., artificially added to products such as soy milk)? &lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Isn t the solid calcium carbonate in supplements chemically the same as aqueous calcium carbonate in fortified drinks? I m lactose-intolerant. Alas, purely natural foods don t contain enough calcium for the Recommended Daily Intake. &lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;hr&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Optional Reading and Addendum:&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;blockquote&gt;&#xA;  &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.webmd.com/osteoporosis/features/calcium-supplements-pills?page=2&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow noreferrer&quot;&gt;1. WebMD&lt;/a&gt;: &quot;Keep in mind that there s really not that much difference between getting calcium in a supplement and calcium in food.&quot;&lt;br&gt;&#xA;  &quot;Calcium-fortified foods -- such as cereals, some juices, and soy milk -- are excellent sources of the mineral, experts tell WebMD.&quot;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;  &#xA;  &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.health.harvard.edu/blog/high-calcium-intake-from-supplements-linked-to-heart-disease-in-men-2013020658610&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow noreferrer&quot;&gt;2. health.harvard.edu&lt;/a&gt;: An 8-ounce portion of off-the-shelf orange juice contains about 300 mg of calcium. The calcium in fortified soy milk also compares favorably to whole milk.&#xA;  Breakfast cereals (which are also fortified) contain substantial amounts of calcium, especially when combined with low-fat milk.&#xA;  A portion of oatmeal on its own contains just 100 mg of calcium. “But if you cut up some dried figs and add it to a bowl of oatmeal with milk, you easily get about half of what you need without having any supplements,” Dr. Hauser says.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;  &#xA;  &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://well.blogs.nytimes.com/2013/04/08/thinking-twice-about-calcium-supplements-2/?_r=0&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow noreferrer&quot;&gt;3. NY Times Blog&lt;/a&gt;,   &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.nytimes.com/2011/01/25/health/25brody.html&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow noreferrer&quot;&gt;4. NY Times&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;/blockquote&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Footnote: I originally posed this &lt;a href=&quot;https://biology.stackexchange.com/q/10429/4466&quot;&gt;at Biology SE&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;/p&gt;&#xA;" OwnerUserId="14" LastEditorUserId="-1" LastEditDate="2017-04-13T12:48:15.073" LastActivityDate="2015-04-01T00:01:10.120" Title="Calcium supplements versus &quot;fortified with calcium&quot;" Tags="&lt;nutrition&gt;" AnswerCount="1" CommentCount="0" />
  <row Id="4" PostTypeId="1" CreationDate="2015-03-31T19:11:24.947" Score="29" ViewCount="735" Body="&lt;p&gt;One of the most often-cited facts about human life, compared to those of other animals, is that the main reason we live so much longer is modern medicine. Because we can treat illnesses that would previously affect lifespan, we are far more likely to live greatly extended lifespans. However, this leads to two possible (conflicting) logical conclusions:&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;ol&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;People who by chance didn t get deadly diseases before modern medicine would live as long as people today, meaning the ability for any &lt;em&gt;individual&lt;/em&gt; to survive ninety or more years, far longer than nearly all animals, is unrelated to modern medicine.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Every illness one experiences weakens the body in some way, robbing it of future years. This would mean the role of modern medicine in extending lifespan is treating these illnesses to prevent the gradual reduction in lifespan.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ol&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;If the first is true, then lifespan itself isn t influenced by modern medicine unless it prevents death as the direct result of a disease, and only &lt;em&gt;average&lt;/em&gt; lifespan is affected. In other words, if nine in ten dies at age thirty due to a deadly disease, and one in ten dies at age eighty by avoiding disease, the average life expectancy is thirty five, even though an individual could by living an extremely careful life survive to reach eighty.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;If the second is true, then short periods of non-deadly illnesses experienced by everyone each shorten life expectancy by a tiny amount, together decreasing &lt;em&gt;everyone s&lt;/em&gt; lifespan to the same thirty five, rather than the effect being a result of averages.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;So does each illness shorten lifespan, or is it only a result of averages that lifespan was so low pre-modern medicine, and humans always had the capacity for exceptionally-long lives?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;" OwnerUserId="11" LastActivityDate="2017-01-16T14:14:31.053" Title="If human life is so long largely due to modern medicine, does every illness shorten lifespan?" Tags="&lt;life-expectancy&gt;&lt;disease&gt;&lt;statistics&gt;" AnswerCount="2" CommentCount="3" />
  <row Id="5" PostTypeId="1" CreationDate="2015-03-31T19:21:14.007" Score="14" ViewCount="233" Body="&lt;p&gt;Every time one takes a pill, drinks a glass of wine, or uses an illicit drug, it is understood that the effects are temporary. Caffeine only keeps one awake for a few hours, alcohol only intoxicates for a few hours, aspirin only staves off a headache for a few hours. This is because the immune system breaks medicines down, and when they re entirely gone, so is the effect.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;So can the body break down anything?&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The assumption is that the body remains alive long enough to finish breaking down (or not breaking down) the substance.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;" OwnerUserId="11" LastEditorUserId="114" LastEditDate="2015-04-08T18:37:28.483" LastActivityDate="2016-06-11T10:40:39.660" Title="Can the immune system break down anything?" Tags="&lt;immune-system&gt;&lt;drug-metabolism&gt;" AnswerCount="4" CommentCount="2" FavoriteCount="1" />
  <row Id="6" PostTypeId="1" AcceptedAnswerId="478" CreationDate="2015-03-31T19:26:15.727" Score="21" ViewCount="4725" Body="&lt;p&gt;While playing indoor soccer a couple days ago, I was fouled and fell forwards so that my hand skidded across the court a bit. It left the blister as you see in the image here:&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://i.stack.imgur.com/PDHo5m.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;the blister&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;What should I consider when deciding to remove this blister? I could open and drain this blister, removing the excess skin afterwards, or leave it as is.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;I figure since it s in a place that is likely to be touched/disrupted I should remove it since it s likely to open anyways.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;" OwnerUserId="16" LastEditorUserId="62" LastEditDate="2015-04-13T04:27:47.377" LastActivityDate="2015-04-15T18:13:37.963" Title="What should I consider when deciding to remove a blister or not?" Tags="&lt;wound&gt;&lt;removal&gt;" AnswerCount="4" CommentCount="0" />
  <row Id="7" PostTypeId="2" ParentId="6" CreationDate="2015-03-31T19:28:52.820" Score="14" Body="&lt;p&gt;Generally speaking, it s best to leave blisters undisturbed. Unroofing the blister completely is definitely ill-advised, as it exposes the entire dermis underneath, removing a primary barrier to infection. Cover it loosely with rolled gauze and leave it alone; it will either drain on its own, or reabsorb the fluid over time.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;" OwnerUserId="22" LastActivityDate="2015-03-31T19:28:52.820" CommentCount="1" />
  <row Id="8" PostTypeId="2" ParentId="5" CreationDate="2015-03-31T19:29:37.167" Score="14" Body="&lt;p&gt;Certainly not.  By definition, it cannot break down poisons (at least not quickly enough) to stop the body being harmed or killed.  In addition, it can not break down (or &quot;neutralize&quot;) many radioactive substances.  A famous example of this was the murder of &lt;a href=&quot;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Alexander_Litvinenko#Poisoning_and_death&quot;&gt;Alexander Litvinenko&lt;/a&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;blockquote&gt;&#xA;  &lt;p&gt;On 1 November 2006, Litvinenko suddenly fell ill and was hospitalised. His illness was later attributed to poisoning with radionuclide polonium-210 after the Health Protection Agency found significant amounts of the rare and highly toxic element in his body.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;/blockquote&gt;&#xA;" OwnerUserId="8" LastActivityDate="2015-03-31T19:29:37.167" CommentCount="1" />
  <row Id="9" PostTypeId="2" ParentId="5" CreationDate="2015-03-31T19:31:01.247" Score="17" Body="&lt;p&gt;Actually, in the case of most drugs, it has nothing to do with the immune system &lt;em&gt;per se&lt;/em&gt;. Generally, drugs are either chemically modified (often in the liver) to make them inert, or excreted (either in the urine or the stool) thus removing them from the body. When the liver or the kidneys are not working properly, drugs fail to be excreted or digested, resulting in accumulation, which may be toxic.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;" OwnerUserId="22" LastActivityDate="2015-03-31T19:31:01.247" CommentCount="0" />
  <row Id="10" PostTypeId="2" ParentId="4" CreationDate="2015-03-31T19:36:37.267" Score="22" Body="&lt;p&gt;Both. Human cells largely exhibit a phenomenon called &lt;em&gt;senescence&lt;/em&gt; - they just give up and die after they reach a certain age via a biochemical mechanism called &lt;em&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/books/NBK26873/&quot;&gt;apoptosis&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/em&gt;. The outer limit of survivability for human cells is generally understood to be in the 100-120 year range. One of the things that makes a cancer cell cancerous is the deactivation of the signals for apoptosis, making the cell effectively immortal.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;At the same time, most illnesses, particularly the &quot;lifestyle illnesses&quot; (diabetes, hypertension, hypercholesterolemia) so common today, do induce some changes which shorten lifespan.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The most significant changes which extended human life were the development of (a) sanitation and (b) antibiotics. These together dramatically reduced death by infectious disease. Removal of early death from infection exposed these diseases of late-life and lifestyle.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;" OwnerUserId="22" LastEditorUserId="174" LastEditDate="2015-04-07T11:05:57.097" LastActivityDate="2015-04-07T11:05:57.097" CommentCount="11" />
</posts>