<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<posts>
  <row Id="1" PostTypeId="1" CreationDate="2011-10-11T19:30:14.017" Score="16" ViewCount="1924" Body="&lt;p&gt;What factors related to the Eastern Crisis contributed to the outbreak of World War 1?&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The Eastern Crisis pertains to problems posed by the decay of the Ottoman Empire. Primary among these problems were the instability in the European territories that had been ruled by the Ottoman Empire. After the defeat of the Ottomans in the Russo-Turkish War (1768–1774), the dissolution of the Ottoman Empire appeared to be imminent. Several European powers engaged in a power struggle to safeguard their own national interests in the Ottoman domains. &lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;More details are available in this discussion of the  &lt;a href=&quot;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Eastern_Question&quot;&gt;Eastern Question&lt;/a&gt; .&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;" OwnerUserId="14" LastEditorUserId="85" LastEditDate="2012-05-16T15:23:21.313" LastActivityDate="2013-08-19T18:04:54.217" Title="What factors related to the Eastern Crisis contributed to the outbreak of World War 1?" Tags="&lt;20th-century&gt;&lt;world-war-one&gt;" AnswerCount="3" CommentCount="8" FavoriteCount="1" />
  <row Id="2" PostTypeId="1" AcceptedAnswerId="79" CreationDate="2011-10-11T19:31:39.163" Score="31" ViewCount="10271" Body="&lt;p&gt;What language(s) were considered the primary language for the Holy Roman Empire? Were there many different languages spoken due to the many different regions?&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;" OwnerUserId="16" LastEditorUserId="85" LastEditDate="2012-06-14T17:36:24.690" LastActivityDate="2017-09-27T03:58:34.083" Title="What language(s) were spoken within the Holy Roman Empire?" Tags="&lt;holy-roman-empire&gt;&lt;language&gt;" AnswerCount="7" CommentCount="3" FavoriteCount="3" />
  <row Id="3" PostTypeId="1" AcceptedAnswerId="10" CreationDate="2011-10-11T19:33:21.767" Score="14" ViewCount="12360" Body="&lt;p&gt;When in history do we first have record of steel being used as a material?  I am also interested in both its initial purpose and when it was first used in weapon making.  &lt;/p&gt;&#xA;" OwnerUserId="5" LastEditorUserId="16" LastEditDate="2011-10-13T20:30:50.617" LastActivityDate="2011-10-13T20:30:50.617" Title="When did steel first appear?" Tags="&lt;technology&gt;&lt;weapons&gt;&lt;resource&gt;" AnswerCount="2" CommentCount="1" FavoriteCount="1" ClosedDate="2011-11-04T19:28:47.143" />
  <row Id="4" PostTypeId="1" AcceptedAnswerId="238" CreationDate="2011-10-11T19:34:39.723" Score="18" ViewCount="23242" Body="&lt;p&gt;The title above is fairly broad, so more specifically, what specific events led to the Warring States period experienced towards the end of the Western Zhou Dynasty in ancient China? As the lineage and vassal systems are broad answers to this question, what specifically about them contributed to this period in the otherwise illustrious and steadfast Zhou Dynasty?&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;" OwnerUserId="12" LastEditorUserId="4935" LastEditDate="2015-01-26T15:01:59.543" LastActivityDate="2016-03-04T19:39:11.127" Title="What events led to the fall of the Zhou Dynasty during the Warring States period?" Tags="&lt;china&gt;&lt;political-history&gt;&lt;ancient-china&gt;" AnswerCount="5" CommentCount="3" />
  <row Id="5" PostTypeId="5" CreationDate="2011-10-11T19:40:24.407" Score="0" Body="" OwnerUserId="-1" LastEditorUserId="-1" LastEditDate="2011-10-11T19:40:24.407" LastActivityDate="2011-10-11T19:40:24.407" CommentCount="0" />
  <row Id="6" PostTypeId="4" CreationDate="2011-10-11T19:40:24.407" Score="0" Body="The Holy Roman Empire existed from 962 to 1806 on the territory of present-day Germany and a number of its neighboring countries." OwnerUserId="16" LastEditorUserId="43" LastEditDate="2011-11-03T22:42:03.677" LastActivityDate="2011-11-03T22:42:03.677" CommentCount="0" />
  <row Id="8" PostTypeId="2" ParentId="2" CreationDate="2011-10-11T19:41:16.823" Score="4" Body="&lt;p&gt;I m unable to find a reference to an official language of the empire, but according to Wikipedia, the languages that would have been spoken within its borders were numerous, and would include the following:&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Latin&lt;br&gt;&#xA;German&lt;br&gt;&#xA;Italian&lt;br&gt;&#xA;various West Germanic languages&lt;br&gt;&#xA;Romance languages&lt;br&gt;&#xA;Slavic languages&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Taken from &lt;a href=&quot;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Holy_Roman_Empire&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;Holy Roman Empire (Wikipedia)&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;As for which one would have been the language of business, I would say Latin during its inception and pre-Renaissance existence, the Germanic languages as the independent states of the era came into their own during the latter half of the empire time, and Italian as well during that time, but fading as Italian influence waned during the last two hundred or so years.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;" OwnerUserId="20" LastEditorUserId="19246" LastEditDate="2016-08-28T13:19:30.413" LastActivityDate="2016-08-28T13:19:30.413" CommentCount="2" />
  <row Id="9" PostTypeId="2" ParentId="2" CreationDate="2011-10-11T19:42:37.773" Score="20" Body="&lt;p&gt;Mainly German, but a lot of literature wasn t vernacular (in your language) until after the printing press, so Latin was used to read books (if you were educated). Italian was also used in the southern part of the HRE.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;(Pulled from &lt;em&gt;A History of Western Society&lt;/em&gt; by John McKay)&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;" OwnerUserId="31" LastEditorUserId="10" LastEditDate="2011-10-12T17:21:02.423" LastActivityDate="2011-10-12T17:21:02.423" CommentCount="2" />
  <row Id="10" PostTypeId="2" ParentId="3" CreationDate="2011-10-11T19:43:38.333" Score="5" Body="&lt;p&gt;According to &lt;a href=&quot;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Steel&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;wikipedia&lt;/a&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;blockquote&gt;&#xA;  &lt;p&gt;The earliest known production of steel is a piece of ironware excavated from an archaeological site in Anatolia (Kaman-Kalehoyuk) and is about 4,000 years old. Other ancient steel comes from East Africa, dating back to 1400 BC. In the 4th century BC steel weapons like the Falcata were produced in the Iberian Peninsula, while Noric steel was used by the Roman military. The Chinese of the Warring States (403–221 BC) had quench-hardened steel, while Chinese of the Han Dynasty (202 BC – 220 AD) created steel by melting together wrought iron with cast iron, gaining an ultimate product of a carbon-intermediate steel by the 1st century AD. The Haya people of East Africa discovered a type of high-heat blast furnace which allowed them to forge carbon steel at 1,802 °C (3,276 °F) nearly 2,000 years ago. This ability was not duplicated until centuries later in Europe during the Industrial Revolution.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;/blockquote&gt;&#xA;" OwnerUserId="16" LastActivityDate="2011-10-11T19:43:38.333" CommentCount="12" />
</posts>