<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<posts>
  <row Id="1" PostTypeId="1" AcceptedAnswerId="2776" CreationDate="2011-11-30T19:15:54.070" Score="31" ViewCount="5048" Body="&lt;p&gt;Some comedian/actors are given creative freedom and improvise at times when producing a new film. Is there any evidence that Vince Vaughn or Owen Wilson improvised in any scenes, diverging from the script, in the film Wedding Crashers?&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;" OwnerUserId="11" LastEditorUserId="3650" LastEditDate="2013-09-25T14:15:14.257" LastActivityDate="2013-09-25T14:15:14.257" Title="To what extent were the actors in Wedding Crashers improvising?" Tags="&lt;wedding-crashers&gt;" AnswerCount="2" CommentCount="0" />
  <row Id="2" PostTypeId="2" ParentId="1" CreationDate="2011-11-30T19:37:10.510" Score="15" Body="&lt;p&gt;According to the &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.imdb.com/title/tt0396269/trivia&quot;&gt;trivia on IMDb&lt;/a&gt;, Owen Wilson and Vince Vaughn improvised the &quot;Lock it up!&quot; banter. As I understand it, that also means the other scenes did not - or only slightly - diverge from the script.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;" OwnerUserId="31" LastActivityDate="2011-11-30T19:37:10.510" CommentCount="3" />
  <row Id="3" PostTypeId="1" AcceptedAnswerId="814" CreationDate="2011-11-30T19:41:14.960" Score="29" ViewCount="1331" Body="&lt;p&gt;In his Star Wars Episode 1 &lt;a href=&quot;http://redlettermedia.com/plinkett/star-wars/star-wars-episode-1-the-phantom-menace/&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow noreferrer&quot;&gt;review/analysis&lt;/a&gt;, Mike Stoklasa used a certain challenge as a device to illustrate how poorly thought out the characters were: &lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;blockquote&gt;&#xA;  &lt;p&gt;Describe the following characters without mentioning what they look like, what kind of costume they wore, or what their profession or role in the movie was. Describe them like you would to people who've never seen Star Wars.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;/blockquote&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;He then listed Han Solo, Qui-Gon Jin, C3PO and Queen Amidala, each followed by descriptions (or attempts at them) by various people.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Is this a correct way of assessing characters in a film, at least in a one with three arcs structure and clear protagonist and antagonist? Are there some important aspects of characters that it doesn't cover?&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;" OwnerUserId="41" LastEditorUserId="27264" LastEditDate="2016-12-27T10:02:34.153" LastActivityDate="2016-12-27T10:02:34.153" Title="Evaluating characters by means of description" Tags="&lt;analysis&gt;&lt;star-wars&gt;" AnswerCount="2" CommentCount="2" />
  <row Id="4" PostTypeId="1" AcceptedAnswerId="120" CreationDate="2011-11-30T19:42:45.470" Score="52" ViewCount="2265" Body="&lt;p&gt;I'm a big fan of the Pink Panther movies (the ones with Peter Sellers, not new ones with Steve Martin).  But after watching &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.imdb.com/title/tt0352520/&quot;&gt;The Life and Death of Peter Sellers&lt;/a&gt;, I'm left with the impression that the original &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.imdb.com/title/tt0057413/&quot;&gt;The Pink Panther&lt;/a&gt; was intended to be a serious film, but Peter Sellers essentially tried to sabotage the production out of spite, turning it into a comedy, and subsequently turning it into the classic hit it became.  The sequels all have much more of a comedy feel, which would be consistent with this sequence of events.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;But how accurate was the portrayal of these events in &lt;strong&gt;The Life and Death of Peter Sellers&lt;/strong&gt;?  Can I read more about the dynamics that took place during the creation of the original movie and the sequel?&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;" OwnerUserId="22" LastEditorUserId="22" LastEditDate="2013-08-17T20:17:23.187" LastActivityDate="2015-10-19T00:06:22.083" Title="Was the original &quot;Pink Panther&quot; movie intended to be a comedy?" Tags="&lt;comedy&gt;&lt;the-pink-panther&gt;" AnswerCount="4" CommentCount="2" FavoriteCount="2" />
  <row Id="6" PostTypeId="1" AcceptedAnswerId="21" CreationDate="2011-11-30T19:44:55.593" Score="15" ViewCount="4460" Body="&lt;p&gt;At the end of the movie, adult Jack (Sean Penn) wanders through a wasteland, goes through a doorway and ends up on a beach. There he shares the screen with his father (Brad Pitt) and Mrs. O’Brien (Jessica Chastain) concedes her son (presumably R.L.) to the higher power.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;What does the ending mean?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;" OwnerUserId="34" LastEditorUserId="49" LastEditDate="2013-06-06T12:05:01.613" LastActivityDate="2013-06-06T20:02:04.800" Title="What does the ending of The Tree of Life mean?" Tags="&lt;plot-explanation&gt;&lt;analysis&gt;&lt;ending&gt;&lt;the-tree-of-life&gt;" AnswerCount="2" CommentCount="0" FavoriteCount="1" />
  <row Id="8" PostTypeId="2" ParentId="4" CreationDate="2011-11-30T19:51:44.350" Score="8" Body="&lt;p&gt;Yes, I saw documentaries with &lt;strong&gt;Blake Edwards&lt;/strong&gt; and he knows lot about comedy and visual gags. I'm sure he knew he was doing a comedy.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The spanish documentary &lt;strong&gt;&quot;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.imdb.es/title/tt0278824/&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;Y usted ... ¿de que se ríe?&lt;/a&gt;&quot;&lt;/strong&gt; contains an interview with Blake Edwards about comedy.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;" OwnerUserId="43" LastEditorUserId="22" LastEditDate="2013-07-27T17:36:26.930" LastActivityDate="2013-07-27T17:36:26.930" CommentCount="3" />
  <row Id="10" PostTypeId="1" CreationDate="2011-11-30T19:53:23.387" Score="19" ViewCount="23876" Body="&lt;p&gt;Frank Costello the mob boss, one of the main antagonists in The Departed, is revealed to be a protected FBI informant. Assuming that this is indeed the case, does Costello's ties with the Massachusetts State Police (through Colin, the mole) mean that the FBI was somehow aware that the Police were covertly infiltrated? &lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Furthermore, does this imply that the FBI had motivation/did in fact impede the Police investigation into Costello?&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;" OwnerUserId="11" LastEditorUserId="49" LastEditDate="2016-02-03T19:57:59.727" LastActivityDate="2017-07-28T16:38:07.113" Title="Did the FBI know about the mole in the police department and did they interfere with the investigation?" Tags="&lt;plot-explanation&gt;&lt;the-departed&gt;" AnswerCount="1" CommentCount="1" FavoriteCount="1" />
</posts>