<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<posts>
  <row Id="1" PostTypeId="1" CreationDate="2011-04-26T18:54:45.590" Score="21" ViewCount="451" Body="&lt;p&gt;I have been singing in a (classical) choir for several years, including the occasional solo line, and am now seriously considering voice lessons. However, finding a good teacher seems like a daunting challenge. What should I look for in a good voice teacher?&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;" OwnerUserId="9" LastEditorUserId="2639" LastEditDate="2014-07-02T13:46:56.520" LastActivityDate="2014-07-02T15:11:47.943" Title="Criteria for selecting a voice teacher" Tags="&lt;learning&gt;&lt;voice&gt;&lt;lessons&gt;" AnswerCount="4" CommentCount="2" FavoriteCount="6" />
  <row Id="2" PostTypeId="1" AcceptedAnswerId="8" CreationDate="2011-04-26T18:59:07.007" Score="55" ViewCount="8377" Body="&lt;p&gt;I've heard it said that, whilst on most instruments these notes are played with the same fingerings/technique/etc there is a subtle difference.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;This isn't specific to this particular note combination, but to all enharmonic equivalents.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;What might this teacher have been referring to?&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;" OwnerUserId="11" LastEditorUserId="23" LastEditDate="2011-04-27T01:54:37.877" LastActivityDate="2012-08-27T21:32:56.147" Title="What's the difference between a G♭ and an F#?" Tags="&lt;theory&gt;&lt;tuning&gt;&lt;accidentals&gt;" AnswerCount="6" CommentCount="6" FavoriteCount="16" />
  <row Id="3" PostTypeId="1" AcceptedAnswerId="109" CreationDate="2011-04-26T19:00:35.140" Score="152" ViewCount="21464" Body="&lt;p&gt;Oftentimes major keys are called &quot;happy&quot; and minor keys are &quot;sad&quot;. Why is this? Is it universal across cultures that use these scales? Do similar connotations exist in other scale systems?&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;(If this isn't universal, then perhaps someone could explain which cultures it is sad in and why.)&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;" OwnerUserId="23" LastEditorUserId="23" LastEditDate="2012-06-05T00:43:57.187" LastActivityDate="2017-03-26T04:01:20.100" Title="Why do minor keys sound “sad”?" Tags="&lt;scales&gt;&lt;ethnomusicology&gt;" AnswerCount="13" CommentCount="12" FavoriteCount="36" />
  <row Id="4" PostTypeId="1" CreationDate="2011-04-26T19:00:53.253" Score="10" ViewCount="3288" Body="&lt;p&gt;Consider four cases:&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;A-flat major&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;A-flat (natural) minor&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;A-flat melodic minor&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;A-flat harmonic minor&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;I start them with the third finger on the A-flat key (both hands), but I have no idea how a professional pianist would do it.  Help!&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;" OwnerUserId="18" LastEditorUserId="21" LastEditDate="2011-05-11T17:08:08.080" LastActivityDate="2014-03-22T18:26:29.923" Title="What is the proper way to play A-Flat scales on piano?" Tags="&lt;piano&gt;&lt;technique&gt;&lt;scales&gt;&lt;fingering&gt;" AnswerCount="6" CommentCount="2" FavoriteCount="3" />
  <row Id="5" PostTypeId="1" AcceptedAnswerId="22" CreationDate="2011-04-26T19:02:20.140" Score="21" ViewCount="2539" Body="&lt;p&gt;I play guitar, and am attempting to teach myself the piano. Which notes from a scale form the chord on the keyboard? Is there a common rule for this?&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;" OwnerUserId="8" LastEditorUserId="7222" LastEditDate="2015-12-14T04:40:49.163" LastActivityDate="2015-12-14T04:40:49.163" Title="How to formulate a chord on the piano?" Tags="&lt;theory&gt;&lt;piano&gt;&lt;chords&gt;" AnswerCount="6" CommentCount="2" FavoriteCount="2" />
  <row Id="6" PostTypeId="1" AcceptedAnswerId="29" CreationDate="2011-04-26T19:02:58.820" Score="61" ViewCount="21552" Body="&lt;p&gt;This seems like such a silly question, but!  When playing the piano, I sometimes struggle to turn the pages of my music without noticeably sacrificing the sound of the piece or making the book / sheets fall.  For a complicated piece where there isn't a break in one hand that would allow raising a hand to turn the page, is there a trick I can use to quickly flip the page of music and keep the music going?&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;" OwnerUserId="3" LastActivityDate="2015-11-11T22:42:50.707" Title="Quickly flip a page of sheet music while playing" Tags="&lt;piano&gt;&lt;sheet-music&gt;" AnswerCount="17" CommentCount="11" FavoriteCount="10" />
  <row Id="7" PostTypeId="2" ParentId="5" CreationDate="2011-04-26T19:04:15.163" Score="4" Body="&lt;p&gt;The first, third, and fifth. For example:&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;C major scale: C D E F G A B C&lt;br&gt;&#xA;C major triad: C E G&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;" OwnerUserId="21" LastActivityDate="2011-04-26T19:04:15.163" CommentCount="7" />
  <row Id="8" PostTypeId="2" ParentId="2" CreationDate="2011-04-26T19:04:38.350" Score="48" Body="&lt;p&gt;See the section on &lt;a href=&quot;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Musical_tuning#Tuning_systems&quot;&gt;tuning systems&lt;/a&gt; on Wikipedia for some background.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;In short, most intervals do &lt;em&gt;not&lt;/em&gt; sound best on equally-tempered scales (where the distance between any two consecutive half steps is the same) but on ones where the notes vary in distance. For instance, fifths usually sound the most in tune when the frequencies are in a 2:3 ratio.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Because of this, G♭ and F♯ will often sound different depending on which scale they're being used in and which notes they are played with. As far as I know, G♭ is never higher than F♯, always lower (or perhaps the same, like on a piano).&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;" OwnerUserId="23" LastActivityDate="2011-04-26T19:04:38.350" CommentCount="4" />
  <row Id="9" PostTypeId="1" AcceptedAnswerId="69" CreationDate="2011-04-26T19:05:10.940" Score="59" ViewCount="24439" Body="&lt;p&gt;I have a piano that is out of tune, and I know tuning pianos properly is complicated enough to have it's own profession. But I think it would be interesting to have a go myself, for fun.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;But is this even meaningful? Could I spend a day with some instructions and get a half-decent job done? Or would I just damage the piano or make it worse?&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Good instructions (books or online) for learning how to tune a piano would also be appreciated.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;" OwnerUserId="12" LastActivityDate="2018-02-05T04:25:16.243" Title="How long would it take to learn to tune a piano?" Tags="&lt;piano&gt;&lt;tuning&gt;" AnswerCount="7" CommentCount="5" FavoriteCount="17" />
  <row Id="10" PostTypeId="2" ParentId="4" CreationDate="2011-04-26T19:07:26.413" Score="3" Body="&lt;p&gt;For Ab Major: Start with the third finger on the right hand, third finger on the left.  Play the C with your thumb, then cross over for the Db.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Ab minor: This has the same key signature as B Major, so you can use the same fingering.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;" OwnerUserId="36" LastEditorUserId="36" LastEditDate="2011-04-26T19:12:51.027" LastActivityDate="2011-04-26T19:12:51.027" CommentCount="3" />
</posts>